<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>https://ybganatra.github.io/website/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ybganatra.github.io/website/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bond Portfolio Optimization</title>
      <link>https://ybganatra.github.io/website/projects/p5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ybganatra.github.io/website/projects/p5/</guid>
      <description>This is a research I am currently working on, where we intend to build optimal portfolios of fixed income bonds using Markowitz optimization by CVXPY in python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oil Price Prediction</title>
      <link>https://ybganatra.github.io/website/projects/p4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ybganatra.github.io/website/projects/p4/</guid>
      <description>This project employed machine learning techniques using financial and economic data to attempt to predict crude oil prices. Prediction of up/down prices movements was attempted using both linear classifiers (SVM, Logistic Classification) and non-linear classifiers (Decision Trees). Price prediction was attempted using Quadratic and Huber loss models with regularization and non-linear ensemble methods such as Random Forest, Boosting and Stacking. Finally, a modified ensemble method was proposed and executed, which delivered promising results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio Optimization</title>
      <link>https://ybganatra.github.io/website/projects/p1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ybganatra.github.io/website/projects/p1/</guid>
      <description>This project is based on Index Tracking Portfolio Optimization, wherein I used the Nifty50 Index as a benchmark to build optimal portfolios using the Markowitz Mean-Variance Model in python, and constructed portfolios with mean excess returns over Nifty50 of 0.05% and 0.02% by maximizing Sharpe and minimizing Risk.
A detailed report on this project can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regime Detection</title>
      <link>https://ybganatra.github.io/website/projects/p3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ybganatra.github.io/website/projects/p3/</guid>
      <description>This project was our entry for the International Association of Quantitative Finance (IAQF&amp;rsquo;s) annual academic competition. The goal of the research is to predict the market regimes (Bull, Bear or Static) using mathematical and machine learning techniques.
We used the Hidden Markov Model as our base engine to identify the hidden states of historical markets based on the value of the Russell 3000 index, and used other macroeconomical indicators like the VIX index to capture signals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk Analysis</title>
      <link>https://ybganatra.github.io/website/projects/p2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ybganatra.github.io/website/projects/p2/</guid>
      <description>This was a research where industry analysis of the Indian Pharmaceutical sector was done with a focus on Lupin Pharmaceuticals. We analyzed the riskiness across the Sector and Lupin by calculating betas using regression, unlevered betas &amp;amp; IERP. Correlations between the risk factors was also examined. We also looked at the effects to market news and dividend announcements on the stock price.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
